# Megan Miller Web Developer - Software Engineer

541.913.4558 | meganmiller485@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/meganmiller485/ qithub.com/meganmiller485

I am a passionate software engineer who specializes in JavaScript web development. I enjoy challenges and easily adapt to the constantly evolving tech world. I am always ready to tackle complex problems with grace and empathy. My goal is to balance my love of practical technology with my commitment to the planet.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**PROFICIENT:** JavaScript | ReactJS | NodeJS | PostgreSQL | ExpressJS | SQL | HTML | CSS | Vite | Github | Git | RESTful API | ArcGIS Pro |

**KNOWLEDGEABLE**: Heroku | Netlify | Fly.io | PayPal React | EmailJS | Carousel | Redux | Bootstrap | Ruby on Rails | Linux

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## WILD TREE RINGS | Full Stack Developer | Deployment coming soon | Jan 2023 - Current

A website for a creative company to sell tree stump prints for clear-cut awareness and mitigation. Users will have a fully functional user profile with information on past orders and the capability to edit their user information. The site will have exclusive admin access for order/user management and the site will have a functional payment system using paypal. Github:

- Build database interface, created a responsive web server and functional API
- **Tech stack:** JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS, Node, Express, Vite, and PostgreSQL for server development; JWT and BCrypt for token encryption and sensitive information; PayPal for payment integration

## CREATIVE JUICES | Full Stack Developer | https://creative-juices.fly.dev/ | Jan 2023

A single page application (SPA), e-commerce platform, for a small Paint 'N Sip company called Creative Juices located outside of Denver, Colorado. Upon registration/login, users are able to customize their ideal in-person or remote painting service with the addition of painting kits that can be shipped to their location. The site has exclusive admin access allowing management of orders and a full functional payment system using PayPal.

- Co-developed with three colleagues, built database interface, created a responsive web server and functional API
- Tech stack: JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS, Node, Express, Vite, and PostgreSQL for server development; JWT and BCrypt for token encryption and sensitive information; PayPal for payment integration

FITNESS TRACKER | Fullstack Developer | github.com/meganmiller485/fitnessTracker | Jan 2023 Retro themed, Full-Stack project for tracking and creating fitness routines. Users are able to log in and build fitness routines with a list of activities. Users have control over the public/private nature of their routines, are able to see publicly available routines and create new activities if they don't already exist.

- Built database interface, created a responsive web server and functional API, co-developed in 2 weeks
- Tech stack: Javascript, ReactJS, Node, PostgreSQL, Express, CSS, Vite

## **EDUCATION**

#### **COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY**

- Software Engineering Certificate
  Nov 2022 Feb 2023
  Full-time, immersive web development program powered by Fullstack Academy
- Bachelor of Science
   Bachelor of Geology 3.74 GPA

#### Jan 2019 - June 2022

### **EXPERIENCE**

The Still Whiskey Steaks | Server | June 2021 - Nov 2022
The Oil Barn | Market/Sales Representative | June 2021 - Aug 2021
Coopersmith's Pub and Brewery | Server | Oct 2019 - July 2020